Meet Robin Hood and his MERRY MENagerie!
Robin Hood is a animation, family, adventure film
directed by Wolfgang Reitherman.
With King Richard off to the Crusades, Prince John and his slithering minion, Sir Hiss, set about taxing Nottingham's citizens
with support from the corrupt sheriff - and staunch opposition by the wily Robin Hood and his band of merry men.
Robin Hood - A Fox (voice), played by Brian Bedford.
Little John - A Bear (voice), played by Phil Harris.
Friar Tuck - A Badger (voice), played by Andy Devine.
Maid Marian - A Vixen (voice), played by Monica Evans.
Prince John - A Lion / King Richard (voice), played by Peter Ustinov.
Sir Hiss - A Snake (voice), played by Terry-Thomas.
Robin Hood is a 1973 American animated musical adventure comedy film produced by
Walt Disney Productions and released by Buena Vista Distribution.
Produced and directed by Wolfgang Reitherman, it is
based on the English folktale "Robin Hood".
Taking place in a world populated by anthropomorphic animals, the story follows the adventures of Robin Hood, Little John, and the
inhabitants of Nottingham as they fight against the excessive taxation of Prince John, and Robin Hood wins the hand of Maid Marian.
The film features the voices of Brian Bedford, Phil Harris, Peter Ustinov, Pat
Buttram, Monica Evans, Terry-Thomas, Roger Miller, and Carole Shelley.
The idea to adapt Robin Hood into an animated feature was dated back to Walt Disney's interest in the
tale of Reynard the Fox following the release of Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs (1937).
The idea was repeatedly shelved for several decades.
In 1968, Ken Anderson pitched a film adaptation of Robin Hood, incorporating ideas from
Reynard the Fox by using anthropomorphic animals rather than humans.
The project was approved, becoming the first completely "post-Walt"
animated feature and the first with an entirely non-human cast.
Robin Hood was released on November 8, 1973.
The film received mixed reviews from critics, but it was nonetheless a box-office success,
grossing $33 million worldwide against a production budget of $5 million.
Although some retrospective reviews have criticized the heavy use of animation recycled from
previous Disney films, the film's reputation has grown positively over time.
It has become a cult classic that inspired the adult furry fandom.
The film explores themes of hero, right and justice, fox, cartoon, villain.
The tone is lighthearted.